collegebookrenter.com 2015-09-01

# College Book Renter privacy policy for college text books you rent or sell

CBR takes your privacy seriously. The information you provide to us while on www.collegebookrenter.com is strictly confidential and will only be used in the event we need to contact you regarding your order. We will not sell your personal information to third parties. Occasionally, we may contact you regarding special offers that may be of interest. CBR has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@collegebookrenter.com](mailto:privacy@collegebookrenter.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). 

## Collecting Your Information

**Auto**  
Some information is collected automatically when you visit our website. Your IP (Internet Protocol) address, browser information, the date and time you visited, and the Internet address of the referring website are collected. This information is used to monitor the type of traffic that comes to our site. It enables us to update and improve the website, making it more appealing to our users.

**Cookies**  
Our website uses browser cookies to save user information pertaining to your visit.

We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personal information you submit while on our website. We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so that you don't have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also help us track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our website.

The use of third party cookies is not covered by our privacy policy. We have no access or control over these cookies. 

**Pixels**  
We have pixels embedded in our web pages that track your actions throughout the website either by us or our third-party tracking utility company. This information tracks the dollar amount of purchases made so we are able to make more informed marketing decisions. Pixels are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personal information. 

## Information You Submit

**Registration**  
Registration is not required to browse our website but is required to place an order.

Our registration form requires users to give us contact information (such as their name and email address). The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary, notify our customers of upcoming promotions, and allow customers to purchase, rent and sell books. You may opt out of receiving future promotional mailings by logging into your account and updating your account preferences or by following the unsubscribe instructions located at the bottom of each communication. Customers who opt out will still receive notifications regarding their orders (such as order and shipment confirmations).

Customers may also choose to provide a cell phone number and start receiving text message (SMS) notifications for order and shipment confirmations. Standard charges may apply with your carrier. At any time, you may opt out of receiving these text messages by logging into your account and updating your account preferences

**Email Address**  
The email address you provide for order processing may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, periodic company news, updates, and/or related product or service information, etc.

**Completing an Order**  
Certain information collected at the time an order is placed is necessary for completion. This information is voluntarily submitted by the user and includes, but is not limited to: 

  * Name
  * Billing Address
  * Shipping Address
  * Phone Number
  * Email Address

**Third Party Links**  
Our website contains links to other sites. All third party sites are subject to their own privacy policies. CBR cannot be responsible for the action of any third party websites.

**Social Media (Features) and Widgets**  
Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like Button and Profile Photo, which allows visitors to share that they like this website, or use their Facebook profile photo as their CBR profile photo. The website also includes Widgets such as the Share This button and interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. To remove your photo from your profile, simply click on "remove profile photo" within your account. 

Please be aware that other users of the website may be able to view your photo. If you do not wish to allow other users to view your photo, then you should not upload one

**Public Forums**  
Our website offers publicly accessible blogs and community forums which you must be logged into Wordpress to use. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@collegebookrenter.com](mailto:privacy@collegebookrenter.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information. If this occurs, we will let you know that we were unable to do so and why.

**Security**  
Protecting your information is a top priority. This website is scanned, tested, and certified daily as a part of our ongoing efforts to provide our customers with a safe and secure online shopping experience. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

**Encryption**  
Our site uses 1024-bit Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption to protect your sensitive information. SSL technology prevents the interception of your information during Internet transmission.

**Credit Card Information**  
Your credit card numbers will be stored on our secure severs for billing purposes, which includes late return fees, damage fees, and non-return fees.

**Account Information**  
Your account number and routing number are electronically submitted through our secure servers to a third party financial institution that transfers the money from CBR accounts to your personal account.

Customer information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever without the consent of the customer other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested by the customer.

**Updating your Account Information**  
If you wish to update, delete inaccuracies, remove your photo, or correct your personal information, you may do so by logging into your account and selecting "edit my account info" or by emailing us at [privacy@collegebookrenter.com](mailto:privacy@collegebookrenter.com). We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

**Data Retention**  
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [privacy@collegebookrenter.com](mailto:privacy@collegebookrenter.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Changes in this Privacy Statement**  
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
